在这节课中，哈里森将教授最重要的关键构建块，即链。
In this lesson, Harrison will teach the most important key building block of
链通常将一个llm大型语言模型与提示结合在一起。
land chain, namely the chain.
使用这个构建块，您还可以将一堆这些构建块组合在一起，对您的文本或其他数据进行一系列操作。
The chain usually combines an llm large language model together with a prompt.
我很兴奋地深入研究它。
And with this building block, you can also put a bunch of these building blocks
好的，首先，我们要加载环境变量，就像以前一样。
together to carry out a sequence of operations on your texts or on your other
然后我们还要加载一些我们要使用的数据。
data.
这些链的一部分的强大之处在于您可以一次运行它们在许多输入上。
I'm excited to dive into it.
因此，我们将加载一个pandas数据框架。
All right, to start, we're going to load the environment variables as we have
pandas数据框架只是包含许多不同数据元素的数据结构。
before.
如果您不熟悉pandas，请不要担心。
And then we're also going to load some data that we're going to use.
这里的主要观点是我们正在加载一些数据，稍后可以使用。
So part of the power of these chains is that you can run them over many inputs
因此，如果我们查看这个pandas数据框架，我们可以看到有一个
at a time.
产品列，然后是一个评论列。
Here, we're going to load a pandas data frame.
每一行都是一个不同的数据点，我们可以开始通过我们的链传递。
A pandas data frame is just a data structure that contains a bunch of
因此，我们要介绍的第一个链是llm链。
different elements of data.
这是一个简单但非常强大的链，是未来我们将要介绍的许多链的基础。
If you're not familiar with pandas, don't worry about it.
因此，我们将导入三个不同的东西。
The main point here is that we're loading some data that we can then use later on.
我们将导入OpenAI模型。
And so if we look inside this pandas data frame, we can see that there is a
所以llm，我们将导入聊天提示模板。
product column and then a review column.
这是提示，然后我们将导入llm链。
And each of these rows is a different data point that we can start passing
首先，我们要做的是初始化我们要使用的语言模型。
through our chains.
因此，我们将使用高温度初始化聊天OpenAI。
So the first chain we're going to cover is the llm chain.
现在，我们将初始化提示，这个提示将接受一个
And this is a simple but really powerful chain that underpins a lot of the chains
名为product的变量。
that we'll go over in the future.
它将要求LLM生成描述制造该产品的最佳名称。
And so we're going to import three different things.
公司的名称。
We're going to import the OpenAI model.
最后，我们将把这两个东西组合成一个链。
So the llm, we're going to import the chat prompt template.
这就是我们所谓的LLM链。
And so this is the prompt and then we're going to import the llm chain.
它非常简单。
And so first, what we're going to do is we're going to initialize the language
它只是LLM和提示的组合。
model that we want to use.
但现在，这个链将让我们按顺序运行提示和LLM。
So we're going to initialize the chat OpenAI with a temperature, with a high
因此，如果我们有一个名为“queen size sheet set”的产品，我们可以通过使用chain.run将其运行通过这个链。
temperature so that we can get some fun descriptions.
在幕后，它将格式化提示，然后将整个提示传递到LLM中。
Now we're going to initialize a prompt and this prompt is going to take in a
因此，我们可以看到我们得到了这个假想公司的名称，叫做Royal Beddings。
variable called product.
因此，现在是暂停的好时机，您可以输入任何产品描述，然后查看链将输出什么结果。
It's going to ask the llm to generate what the best name is to describe a
LLM链是最基本的链类型，将在未来经常使用。
company that makes that product.
因此，我们可以看到这将如何在下一个类型的链中使用，即顺序链。
And then finally, we're going to combine these two things into a chain.
因此，顺序链依次运行一系列链。
And so this is what we call an llm chain.
因此，首先，您将导入简单的顺序链。
And it's quite simple.
当我们有只期望一个输入并返回一个输出的子链时，这很有效。
It's just the combination of the llm and the prompt.
结果。
But now this chain will let us run through the prompt and into the llm in a
因此，我们可以看到这将如何在下一个类型的链中使用，即顺序链。
sequential manner.
将经常使用LLM链。
And so if we have a product called queen size sheet set, we can run this through
因此，我们可以看到这将如何在下一个类型的链中使用，即顺序链。
the chain by using chain.run.
因此，顺序链依次运行一系列链。
And what this will do is it will format the prompt under the hood and then it
will pass the whole prompt into the llm.
因此，首先，您将导入简单的顺序链。
And so we can see that we get back the name of this hypothetical company called
当我们有只期望一个输入并返回一个输出的子链时，这很有效。
Royal Beddings.
结果。
And so here would be a good time to pause and you can input any product
因此，这里我们将首先创建一个链，它使用LLM和提示。
descriptions that you would want and you can see what the chain will output as a
这个提示将接受产品并返回最佳名称来描述该公司。
result.
那将是第一个链。
So the llm chain is the most basic type of chain and that's going to be used a
然后，我们将创建第二个链。
lot in the future.
在第二个链中，我们将接受公司名称，然后输出该公司的20个单词的描述。
And so we can see how this will be used in the next type of chain, which will be
因此，您可以想象这些链如何一个接一个地运行，
sequential chains.
因此，这里我们将首先创建一个链，它使用LLM和提示。
And so sequential chains run a sequence of chains one after another.
这个提示将接受产品并返回最佳名称来描述该公司。
So to start, you're going to import the simple sequential chain.
因此，您可以想象这些链如何一个接一个地运行，
And this works well when we have sub chains that expect only one input and
第一个链的输出，即公司名称，然后传递到第二个链中。
return only one output.
第二个链。
And so here we're going to first create one chain, which uses an llm and a
我们可以通过创建一个简单的顺序链来轻松实现这一点，在这个链中，我们有
prompt.
那里描述的两个链。
And this prompt is going to take in the product and will return the best name to
我们将称之为整体简单链。
describe that company.
现在，您可以在任何产品描述上运行此链。
So that will be the first chain.
因此，如果我们将其与上面的产品一起使用，即女王尺寸床单套装，我们可以
Then we're going to create a second chain.
运行它，我们可以看到首先输出皇家博彩，然后将其传递到第二个链中。
In the second chain, we'll take in the company name and then output a 20 word
然后它提出了这家公司可能涉及的描述。
description of that company.
当只有一个输入和一个输出时，简单的顺序链运作良好。
And so you can imagine how these chains might want to be run one after another,
但是当只有一个输入时呢？
where the output of the first chain, the company name is then passed into the
单个输出，但是当有多个输入或多个输出时呢？
second chain.
那么我们可以使用普通的顺序链来实现这一点。
We can easily do this by creating a simple sequential chain where we have the
当然，我们可以使用普通的顺序链来实现这一点。
two chains described there.
输出？
And we'll call this overall simple chain.
因此，我们可以使用普通的顺序链来实现这一点。
Now, what you can do is run this chain over any product description.
所以让我们导入它。
And so if we use it with the product above the queen size sheet set, we can
然后，您将创建一堆链，我们将一个接一个地使用它们。
run it over and we can see that at first outputs royal betting, and then it
我们将使用上面的数据，其中有一个评论。
passes it into the second chain.
因此，第一个链，我们将采取评论并将其翻译成
And it comes up with this description of what that company could be about.
英语。
The simple sequential chain works well when there's only a single input and a
第二个链，我们将创建一个摘要
single output.
一句话。这将使用先前生成的英文评论。
But what about when there's only one input?
因此，如果您注意到，这是使用来自
And a single output, but what about when there are multiple inputs or multiple
原始评论的评论变量。
outputs?
最后，第四个链将接受多个输入。
And so we can do this by using just the regular sequential chain.
因此，这将接受我们使用第二个
So let's import that.
链计算的摘要变量和我们使用第三个链计算的语言变量。
And then you're going to create a bunch of chains that we're going to use one
它将要求在指定的
after another.
语言中对摘要进行跟进回复。
We're going to be using the data from above, which has a review.
关于所有这些子链的一个重要事项是输入键
And so the first chain, we're going to take the review and translate it into
输出键需要非常精确。
English.
所以在这里我们正在进行审查。
With a second chain, we're going to create a summary of that review in one
这是一个在开始时将传递的变量。
sentence. And this will use the previously generated English review.
我们可以看到我们明确将输出键设置为英文审查。
The third chain is going to detect what the language of the review was in the
然后在下面的下一个提示中使用它，我们接受英文审查
first place.
使用相同的变量名，并将该链的输出键设置为摘要，
And so if you notice, this is using the review variable that is coming from the
我们可以看到它在最终链中使用。
original review.
第三个提示接受审查原始变量和输出语言，
And finally, the fourth chain will take in multiple inputs.
这又在最终提示中使用。
So this will take in the summary variable, which we calculated with the second
确保这些变量名称完全正确非常重要，
chain and the language variable, which we calculated with the third chain.
因为有很多不同的输入和输出。
And it's going to ask for a follow up response to the summary in the specified
如果您遇到任何键错误，一定要检查它们是否对齐。
language.
因此，简单的顺序链接收多个链，其中每个链具有一个
One important thing to note about all these sub chains is that the input keys
单个输入和单个输出。
and output keys need to be pretty precise.
要查看其可视化表示，我们可以查看幻灯片，其中有一个
So here we're taking in review.
链一个接一个地进入另一个链。
This is a variable that will be passed in at the start.
在这里，我们可以看到顺序链的视觉描述，将其与
We can see that we explicitly set the output key to English review.
上面的链进行比较，您可以注意到链中的任何步骤都可以接受多个输入
This is then used in the next prompt down below where we take in English review
变量。
with that same variable name and we set the output key of that chain to summary,
当您拥有更复杂的下游链需要时，这非常有用
which we can see is used in the final chain.
成为多个先前链的组合。
The third prompt takes in review the original variable and output language,
现在我们拥有所有这些链，我们可以轻松地将它们组合在顺序中
which is again used in the final prompt.
链。
It's really important to get these variable names lined up exactly right,
因此，您会注意到我们将创建的四个链传递到
because there's so many different inputs and outputs going on.
链变量。
And if you get any key errors, you should definitely check that they are lined up.
我们将创建具有一个人类输入的输入变量，即
So the simple sequential chain takes in multiple chains where each one has a
审查。
single input and a single output.
然后我们想返回所有中间输出。
To see a visual representation of this, we can look at the slide where it has one
英文审查，摘要，然后是后续消息。
chain feeding into the other chain one after another.
现在我们可以在一些数据上运行它。
Here we can see a visual description of the sequential chain, comparing it to the
所以让我们选择一篇评论并通过整个链传递它。
above chain, you can notice that any step in the chain can take in multiple input
我们可以看到这里的原始评论似乎是法语。
variables.
我们可以把英文评论看作是一种翻译。
This is useful when you have more complicated downstream chains that need
我们可以看到该评论的摘要，然后我们可以看到一条用法语原文写的跟进信息。
to be a composition of multiple previous chains.
您应该在此暂停视频并尝试输入不同的输入。
Now that we have all these chains, we can easily combine them in the sequential
到目前为止，我们已经涵盖了LLM链和顺序链。
chain.
但是，如果您想做一些更复杂的事情怎么办？
So you'll notice here that we'll pass in the four chains we created into the
一个相当常见但基本的操作是根据输入将其路由到链中。
chains variable.
一个很好的想象方式是，如果您有多个子链，每个子链都专门用于特定类型的输入，您可以有一个路由器链，
We'll create the inputs variable with the one human input, which is the
首先决定要将其传递到哪个子链，然后将其传递到该链。
review.
一个具体的例子是，让我们看看在不同类型的链之间路由的情况，具体取决于似乎出现的主题。
And then we want to return all the intermediate outputs.
所以我们这里有不同的提示。
So the English review, the summary, and then the follow up message.
一个提示适合回答物理问题。
Now we can run this over some of the data.
第二个提示适合回答数学问题。
So let's choose a review and pass it in through the overall chain.
第三个适用于历史，第四个适用于计算机科学。
We can see here that the original review looks like it was in French.
让我们定义所有这些提示模板。
We can see the English review as a translation.
在我们拥有这些提示模板之后，我们可以提供更多信息
We can see a summary of that review, and then we can see a follow up message in
关于它们。
the original language of French.
我们可以为每个模板命名，然后提供描述。
You should pause the video here and try putting in different inputs.
这个物理学的描述适合回答关于物理学的问题。
So far we've covered the LLM chain and then a sequential chain.
这些信息将传递给路由器链。
But what if you want to do something more complicated?
因此，路由器链可以决定何时使用此子链。
A pretty common, but basic operation is to route an input to a chain, depending
我们现在可以导入我们需要的其他类型的链。
on what exactly that input is.
在这里，我们需要一个多提示链。
A good way to imagine this is if you have multiple sub chains, each of which
这是一种特定类型的链，用于在多个不同的提示模板之间进行路由。
specialized for a particular type of input, you could have a router chain,
但是，这只是您可以路由的一种类型。
which first decides which sub chain to pass it to, and then passes it to that
您可以在任何类型的链之间进行路由。
chain.
这里我们要实现的另外几个类是LLM路由器链。
For a concrete example, let's look at where we are routing between different
这个类本身使用语言模型来在不同的子链之间进行路由。
types of chains, depending on the subject that seems to come in.
这就是上面提供的描述和名称将被使用的地方。
So we have here different prompts.
我们还将导入一个路由器输出解析器。
One prompt is good for answering physics questions.
这将LLM输出解析为可在下游使用的字典，以确定要使用哪个链以及该链的输入应该是什么。
The second prompt is good for answering math questions.
现在我们可以开始使用它了。
The third for history, and then a fourth for computer science.
首先，让我们导入并定义要使用的语言模型。
Let's define all these prompt templates.
现在我们创建目标链。
After we have these prompt templates, we can then provide more information
这些是由路由器链调用的链。
about them.
正如您所看到的，每个目标链本身都是一个语言模型链，
We can give each one a name and then a description.
除了目标链之外，我们还需要一个默认目标链。
This description for the physics one is good for answering questions about
这是一个当路由器无法决定使用哪个子链时调用的链。
physics.
在上面的示例中，当输入问题与物理、数学、历史或计算机科学无关时，可能会调用它。
This information is going to be passed to the router chain.
除了目标链之外，我们还需要一个默认链。
So the router chain can decide when to use this sub chain.
这是一个当路由器无法决定使用哪个子链时调用的链。
Let's now import the other types of chains that we need.
在上面的示例中，当输入问题与物理、数学、历史或计算机科学无关时，可能会调用它。
Here we need a multi-prompt chain.
现在我们定义了LLM用于在不同链之间进行路由的模板。
This is a specific type of chain that is used when routing between multiple
这包括要完成的任务的说明以及输出应该采用的特定格式。
different prompt templates.
让我们将其中一些部分组合起来构建路由器链。
As you can see, all the options we have are prompt templates themselves.
首先，我们通过格式化上面定义的目标创建完整的路由器模板。
But this is just one type of thing that you can route between.
这个模板可以适应许多不同类型的目标。
You can route between any type of chain.
在这里，您可以暂停并添加不同类型的目标。
The other classes that we'll implement here are an LLM router chain.
因此，在这里，您可以添加一个不同的学科，如英语或拉丁语，而不仅仅是物理、数学、历史和计算机科学。
This uses a language model itself to route between the different sub chains.
接下来，我们从这个模板创建提示模板，
This is where the description and the name provided above will be used.
然后通过传入LLM和整个路由器提示来创建路由器链。
We'll also import a router output parser.
这个模板可以适应许多不同类型的目标。
This parses the LLM output into a dictionary that can be used downstream
在这里，您可以暂停并添加不同类型的目标。
to determine which chain to use and what the input to that chain should be.
因此，在这里，您可以添加一个不同的学科，如英语或拉丁语，而不仅仅是物理、数学、历史和计算机科学。
Now we can get around to using it.
接下来，我们从这个模板创建提示模板，
First, let's import and define the language model that we will use.
然后通过传入LLM和整个路由器提示来创建路由器链。
We now create the destination chains.
请注意，这里有路由器输出解析器。
These are the chains that will be called by the router chain.
这很重要，因为它将帮助这个链路决定
As you can see, each destination chain itself is a language model chain,
在哪些子链路之间进行路由。
an LLM chain.
最后，将所有内容整合在一起，我们可以创建整体链路。
In addition to the destination chains, we also need a default destination chain.
它有一个路由器链路，在这里定义。
In addition to the destination chains, we also need a default chain.
它有目标链路，我们在这里传递。
This is a chain that's called when the router can't decide
然后我们还传递默认链路。
which of the sub chains to use.
现在我们可以使用这个链路。
And the example above, this might be called when the input question
所以让我们问一些问题。
has nothing to do with physics, math, history or computer science.
如果我们问一个物理问题，
Now we define the template that is used by the LLM
我们应该希望看到它被路由到物理链路
to route between the different chains.
输入是什么，黑体辐射是什么？
This has instructions of the task to be done,
然后它被传递到下面的链路中。
as well as the specific formatting that the output should be in.
我们可以看到回答非常详细
Let's put a few of these pieces together to build the router chain.
有很多物理细节。
First, we create the full router template by formatting it
您应该在此暂停视频并尝试输入不同的内容。
with the destinations that we defined above.
您可以尝试使用我们上面定义的所有其他类型的特殊链路
This template is flexible to a bunch of different types of destinations.
。
One thing you can do here is pause and add different types of destinations.
因此，例如，如果我们问一个数学问题，
So up here, rather than just physics, math, history and computer science,
我们应该看到它被路由到数学链路
you could add a different subject like English or Latin.
然后传递到那里。
Next, we create the prompt template from this template,
我们还可以看到当我们传递一个问题时会发生什么
and then we create the router chain by passing in the LLM
与任何子链路都无关的。
and the overall router prompt.
所以在这里，我们问一个关于生物学的问题
Note that here we have the router output parser.
我们可以看到它选择的链路是无。
This is important as it will help this chain decide
这意味着它将被传递到默认链路，
which sub chains to route between.
它本身只是对语言模型的通用调用。
And finally, putting it all together, we can create the overall chain.
语言模型幸运地对生物学知道很多，
This has a router chain, which is defined here.
所以它可以帮助我们。
It has destination chains, which we pass in here.
现在我们已经涵盖了这些基本问题，
And then we also pass in the default chain.
让我们继续视频的下一部分。
We can now use this chain.
那就是如何创建一个新的链路。
So let's ask it some questions.
因此，例如，在下一部分中，
If we ask it a question about physics,
我们将介绍如何创建一个链路
we should hopefully see that it is routed to the physics chain
可以对您的文档进行问答。
with the input, what is blackbody radiation?